

reneebasscruz@gmail.com
reneecruz.github.io

**4** 6467048919

♦ New York, NY

in reneecruz

← reneecruz

## **SKILLS**

JavaScript (ES6+), Ruby, Rails, SQL/SQLite, Postgresql, React, React Hooks, React Router, Redux, JWT Auth, Version Control (Glt/Github), Active Record, REST API, RESTful Architecture, HTML, CSS, Sinatra, MVC, OOP

## **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer experienced with Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming. Proven track record in the music industry as a performer and a product manager. I live at the intersection of technical expertise and artistic excellence to help visionary companies build brand legacy, drive revenue and to create lasting impact. Technical writing published in The Start Up, JavaScript in Plain English and Medium JavaScript on my blog.

## **PROJECTS**

#### SMALL SHOP - ONLINE SHOP WEB APP FOR E-COMMERCE ENTREPRENEURS

Small Shop - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo | Deployed Web App

Online Shop Web App for e-commerce entrepreneurs provides secure functionality to persist user's cart and account.

- Authorized users via JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side for login and perisit functionality
- Built Backend API using Ruby on Rails and RESTular for user database, order logic, and perform CRUD actions
- Implemented React JS to create reusable UI components for modularity and dynamic routing using React-Router
- Utilized Redux to create a single source of truth in handling persistence of the user's account and cart logic
- Queried REST Client to parse data structures from H&M Inventory API to populate items model in the backend

#### THE HORACLE - HOROSCOPE ORACLE FOR MADLIBS ASTROLOGY

The Horacle | Horoscope Oracle for Madlibs Astrology - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo | Deployed Web App

Interactive Oracle prompt co-creates a user's future by choosing words for fun and generating a random prediction.

- Generated random Madlib data by GET request to RESTFUL Rails API backend, used Ruby & JS for logic wordbank
- Created an interactive UI using pure CSS to enable a toggle switch for the user to between light and dark mode
- Implemented Fetch to query and retrieve data from external Horoscope & Astrology API to render daily horoscope
- Established a link to Twitter API to publish user's generated madlib horoscope on their individual Twitter account

#### **DOGGO DOPTION - PET ADOPTION WEB APP**

Doggo Doption - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

Pet adoption web app connects users to their new best friends and allows them virtual adoption in their secure account.

- Implemented React JS and React Router to create unique URLs & UI composed of reusable components
- Utilized JSON Web Token Authentication, BCrypt and localStorage to authenticate and authorize the user
- Fetched data from Dog CEO API and incorporated Faker Gem to generate dog data to Frontend
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Built Backend API using Ruby on Rails and designed database schema using Active Record and Postgres \, \text{DB}}$

## **EMPLOYMENT**

#### THE JUILLIARD SCHOOL

Accompanist

New York, NY

Mar. 2016 to Current, Mar. 2016 to Current

- Sight-read music notation during live performances on double bass for International festival audience of thousands
- Lead bilingual masterclasses & improvised basslines in the Jazz & Black American Music idiom to instruct students

# FELDOR BILLIARDS INC. DBA FAT CAT & FAT CAT FAB LAB Growth Lead

New York, NY Dec. 2008 to Mar. 2016

- Increased revenue from low 100K to over 5M from 2011 to 2016 by leveraging connections and marketing for live music, cultural events & educational initiatives, designed and managed website, HTML, CSS, Adobe Creative Cloud
- Established Fabrication Lab community maker space by R&D, providing access to digital fabrication tools for rapid prototyping, designed and managed website HTML, CSS, Wordpress, FTP, hosting, email marketing, social media
- $\bullet \ {\bf Originated} \ {\bf membership} \ {\bf by} \ {\bf implementing} \ {\bf marketing} \ {\bf strategy} \ {\bf through} \ {\bf community} \ {\bf events}, \ {\bf curriculum} \ \& \ {\bf classes} \ {\bf originated} \ {\bf originated}$

### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School
Software Engineering Immersive

The Juilliard School Master of Music Double Bass 2007

The New School

Bachelor of Fine Arts Jazz & Contemporary Music 2004

Fall 2019 to Dec. 2019